A song we do have the camera that rotates
around the focal point and we've set up the
basis to the input
system to make this work.
Now we need to rotate around that focal
point using the user input and we're going to
use some rotation speed
to make that happen.
I want you to open
up your rotate camera
script and we have the
awake method for finding
the controls and enabling
what we needed to use.
Now we're going to
go down below or on a
neighbour and we're going
to write another method
called void update and
make sure you have
two curly braces below and that's
going to be able to help us check for it.
So now we're going to want
to read the move action which
will be affected to as we've
done in previous videos.
So we'll write a local variable which is a
vector to and we're going to call this move
input because we only need
to use it in this method here.
We'll set that equal to
the controls dot player
dot move because now we found the
controls dot player and that's enabled.
We can quite easily access the name move
within the script and then we'll say dot read
value and in open and
close angled brackets.
Then what I want you to do is write vector
two that we've done before and then at the
end of that add the two parentheses and a
semicolon so we're going to make sure that
we update the move input with the
value of whatever our move is at any point.
So then we can begin to use this.
So we can then create another local variable
to store this and make it visually easier
to understand so we can have a float called
horizontal input and then we can set that
to move import dot x
because that is going to
be the thing that
moves us left and right or
using the A and D or the arrow
keys that we might want to use.
Make sure you do add a semicolon to the end
just in case you forgot about it and then
below here then we
need to use this in our
transform dot rotate to
make sure that we can
use the horizontal input.
We can say transform
dot rotate with a capital
R is going to rotate
around something and then
we're going to say vector three dot
up add a comma and then we're
going to use our horizontal input.
Of course we could
use move input dot x but
sometimes giving it an
M like horizontal input
makes it easy to understand if you're looking
back and then we're going to times by a
rotation speed which we haven't quite created
and then we'll also multiply by time dot
delta time and end the bracket and the
semicolon just so that we can make sure this
is done frame rate independent
and across a period of time.
I want to head to the top of our script and
have a public variable and we're going to
have this as a float and call this rotation
speed like we wanted so that equal we could
say 150 F just for now
and you can make sure
that rotation speed
is spelled the same so
that we can start using
this in our game and
we can save that out now if we go back into
unity and make sure your focal point does
have your rotate camera script and it should
be set to 150 with the rotation speed.
So now you can see if I hold a we rotate
left and right and we can also use the arrow
keys because it was
set up in our input actions
editor to be able to
use all of these controls.
So to make this happen
I want you to head to
your rotate camera script
and add a new public
float rotation speed
and set it something like
150 F just so you got
a speed that's usable
then create an update method void update and
then we're going to have a private vector
to variable move input
and set that equal to
controls dot player dot move dot read value
vector 2 then we'll have another private
variable called horizontal
input equals the move
input dot x but the left and right and it's
just nice a way to give it a nice name so
instead of it looking
mouse dot x here we've
got it looking with horizontal input we do
transform dot rotate vector 3 up comma the
horizontal input times by the rotation
speed times by time dot delta time